Guide to the Le Bayou Records
University of Houston Libraries
Le Bayou Records
1934-1964
1998-004
Le Bayou
18.00 Linear Feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains papers related to the publication of Le Bayou and includes subscription information, correspondence, and the submissions of both published and unpublished authors. It also includes the papers of Le Quartier Latin, the French Club of the University of Houston, and its publication Le Feuille de Chou.
Historical Note:
Born at Le Havre in Normandy, in 1892, Jules Vern came to this country in 1930. Jules Vern was called in 1934 to the University of Houston to occupy a chair of professor of French; he organized the study of French so it would be a pleasure for his students to learn this language. When the Cullen Building was opened, he decorated his vast classroom with oil paintings, glass closets containing collections of rare objects, and shelves holding documentary books and foreign magazines. Soon his department was outstanding. He created a club, Le Quartier Latin, and a newspaper that he humorously called Le Feuille de Chou, written and published by his students.
With great success, he had previously founded Le Petit Théâtre Français de Houston, where many of the plays were his own and where French speaking Houstonians, professors of French, including the founder, and students performed. The French Government recognized his efforts in awarding him the decoration Officier d’Académie.
But the great achievement of his life has been the creations of Le Bayou. Jules Vern had the ambitious idea to publish a French magazine in Houston, a magazine in which would be found novels, short stories, essays, critiques, folklore, legends, and poetry concerning France and the South of the United States. In spite of financial difficulties, his tremendous will and perseverance brought success, and Le Bayou was born. In the following years, Le Bayou became known the world over, and was praised by the most prominent writers, not only of France, but of all the French-speaking countries. In 1946, the Academie Française granted to this magazine Le Prix de la Langue Française and a medal engraved with its name. Later, Jules A. Vern received coveted decoration of Officier de l’Instruction Publique as a reward for his literary achievements.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
University of Houston; University of Houston -- Faculty; University of Houston. Department of French.; University of Houston. Quartier Latin
Genre/Form of Material:
Articles; Correspondence; Essays; Novels; Poems; Short stories
Personal Name:
Vern, Jules
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
The Le Bayou collection consists of 20 boxes and is organized into 11 series: Administration, Le Quartier Latin, Correspondence, Submissions, Subscriptions, Le Petit Théâtre Français, Livre d’Or, and Journals, Artistic Stamps, Ledgers, and Photographic Materials. This collection contains papers related to the publication of Le Bayou and includes subscription information, correspondence, and the submissions of both published and unpublished authors. It also includes the papers of Le Quartier Latin, the French Club of the University of Houston, and its publication Le Feuille de Chou. Materials in the Collection date from 1934-1964, and much of it is in the French language.
For preservation and access reasons the collection has been re-boxed and re-foldered. New folder titles conform, as closely as possible, to original folder titles, except when the original was obviously incomplete, incorrect, or confusing. Original folder and item order has been maintained whenever possible. Exceptions were made when folders were obviously misfiled or when no order was apparent.
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries has in its collection the original Le Bayou, under the call number AP21. B25. The bound volumes begin in 1936, with volume 1, and end with volume 95, in 1963.
Detailed List of Contents
- Administration, 1935-1963
  This series consists of one box of Le Bayou’s administrative files, and includes documents that reflect the business aspect of an active international literary journal.
  - General, 1935-1963
    This subseries consists of 32 folders of general business concerns, such as advertising, financial documents, correspondence models, copyright, printing, and publicity. This subseries is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
    - Advertisements, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Advertisements; correspondence, 1939-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bills paid, 1936, 1941-1942, 1945-1952, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Copyright certificates, 1940-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Copyright regulations and blanks, 1935, 1941, 1943-1945, 1948-1949, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Echange de Réclames, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Editors: Associate and Contributing, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Income Le Bayou, 1953-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Internal Memos; University of Houston, 1950-1953, 1957, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Lettres Circulaires aux Redacteurs, 1946-1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Modèles; for correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1947, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Panneaux de Réclame; Matérial, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Pamphlet sur Bayou, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Post Office Declarations and Applications, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Postal Life and Casualty Insurance; Kansas, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Printing Plans, 1940-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Publicity Copy, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Publicity, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Reports, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Requisitions; University of Houston, 1943-1954 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Rubriques du Bayou, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Scardino Publications; Houston, 1941-1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Second National Bank, 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Southwestern Paper Company; Houston, 1939-1949 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - State Sales Tax Report, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Stationary, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Special Recognition Award; Alumni Association, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Jules A. Vern Memorial Award, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Whitehead Sales and Supply Company; Houston, 1941-1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Friends of Le Bayou, 1942-1963
    This subseries consists of 25 folders, mainly correspondence, that pertains to the organization Friends of Le Bayou. This organization was created to ensure that funds could be donated by interested persons and organizations for the continued financial support of this literary magazine. This subseries is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
    - Anderson, Mrs. Frank E.; Houston, 1950-1958 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Anderson, Mr. Leland; Houston, 1950-1963 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Arnold, Mr. and Mrs. Isaac; Houston, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Brandon, Dr. Sylvan; Houston, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Daily, Dr. Ray K.; Houston, 1950-1958 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - de Menil; Mr. and Mrs. Jean; Houston, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Feld, Mr. M. M.; Houston, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - French Embassy, Cultural Division; New York, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Friends of Le Bayou; Financial Information, 1950-1953 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Hogg, Miss Ima; Houston, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Hyde, James Hazeh; New York, 1949-1953 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Johnson, Mr. and Mrs. Elliott A.; Houston, 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Larkin, A. W.; Houston, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Lemieux, Archibald; Massachusetts, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Leonardon, Mr. E. G.; Houston, 1942-1962 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - McCarthy, Glenn; Houston, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Moya, Thérèse; Washington, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Nelms, Anèse Carter; Houston, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Palen, Pierre; Consul à Houston, Texas, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Pan-Geo Atlas Corporation; Houston, 1953-1963 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Phenix, Joseph; New Hampshire, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Scandinavian American Paper Company; Houston, 1952-1962 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Schlumberger Well Surveying Corporation; Houston, 1950, 1952-1963 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Seligman, Roger; Houston, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Smith, Mrs. Thad; Texas, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Turk-Rogé, Henric; Houston, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Fundraising, 1945-1953
    This subseries consists of 7 folders of materials that relate to Le Bayou’s Campagne de Fonds, a yearly fundraising gathering that took place from 1945 to 1953. This subseries is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
    - Campagne de Fonds; correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Campagne Fonds d’Impression; Lettre, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Campagne Fonds d’Impression; Prospects, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Campagne Fonds d’Impression Réponses, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Campagne Fonds d’Impression, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Campagne Fonds d’Impression; Dick Golding, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Campagne Fonds pour Impression, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Le Quartier Latin, 1937-1963
  This series consists of 44 folders of materials that relate to Le Quartier Latin, the French club of the University of Houston. It includes general club administrative information, correspondence (organized by date), La Feuille de Chou, its literary newsletter, fundraising events, and relating to exchanges with other magazines. This series is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
  - Administration, 1937-1963
    This subseries consists of 18 folders of materials that document the general organization of Le Quartier Latin, such as officer positions and the accompanying duties, membership lists, and financial information. This subseries is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
    - Class Enrollment Records, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - La Classe: La Révolution Littérature et Politique du XIX, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Club Organization and Members, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Constitution, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Les Mousquetaires, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Les Mousquetaires, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Membership Lists, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Student’s Activities; Printing Fund, 1945-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Treasurer’s Notebook, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Treasurer’s Reports, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Treasurer’s Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Treasurer’s Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Treasurer’s Reports, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Treasurer’s Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Treasurer’s Report, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Treasurer’s Report, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1953
    This subseries consists of 8 correspondence folders organized by date. It contains correspondence from individuals, other journals, and organizations. This subseries is organized by date.
    - 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 1953 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - La Feuille de Chou, 1938-1954
    This subseries consists of copies of La Feuille de Chou, the newsletter of Le Quartier Latin. It consists of 8 folders organized by date.
    - Scrapbook, 1938-1944 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Stationary, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Volumes 1-3, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Volume 4, 1943-1944 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Volume 5, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Volume 6, 1945-1946 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Volume 7, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Volume 8, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Volumes 9-10, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Volumes 11-14, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Fundraising, 1944-1945
    This subseries consists of 7 folders of material that relates to several events that were held as fundraisers for the club, in its early years. It is organized alphabetically, and then by date.
    - Cabarets, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Christmas Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Banquet/Initiation, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Banquet, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Building Fund, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Soirée, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Soirée II, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Service d’Echange, 1948
    This subseries consists of one folder that contains documents relating to the exchange of La Feuille de Chou with other journals and magazines.
    - Le Quartier Latin; Service d’Echange, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Correspondence, 1937-1964
  This series consists of about two boxes of correspondence, both personal and business. Correspondents of note include E.E. Oberholtzer, the founding president of the University of Houston. This series is organized alphabetically.
  - Académie Berrichonne; Diplome, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Académie Française, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Aldou, Gérard; Paris, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Alliance Française de Houston, 1945, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Des Anges, Mére Françoise; Annhurst College, Connecticut, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Brochon, Léon; Paris, France, 1938-1939, 1946, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Bureau International de Liaison et de Documentation, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Boek, Het Franse; Amsterdam, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Bowen, Willis; Oklahoma, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Centre d’Information de la Culture et de Technique Française, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Colin, André J.; Suisse, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Debbaudt, Roger; California, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Deburat, R.; Paris, France, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - De Cabrol; Alfred; California, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Dickman, Fred; Texas, 1942, 1947-1951, 1953-1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Durel, Lionel C.; Louisiana, 1941, 1945-1949, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Euroamerica; Paris, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Faculté des Lettres; Université de Genève; Université de Lausanne, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Faienstowe, Ariella; London, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - La Famille Universelle, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Farges, Michel; Paris, France, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Favaud, Berthe des Combes; Chicago, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ferron, Jacques; France, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Filliatre, Robert; Achères, France, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Fleury, Marie Claire; Paris, France, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Flouquet, P.L.; Tourai, Belgique, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Flynn, Charlotte, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Foreign Service of the United States; Paris, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Fouquet, Daniel; Allemagne, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fouré-Selter, Madame; Paris, France, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fraser, Dr. Lewis E.; Texas, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Frazer, Ian Forbes, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - French Embassy; New York, 1957-1958, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - French Institute; New York, 1942, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - French National Tourist Office; New York, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fulton, Renée J.; New York, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Gache, M.P.; Gauriac, France, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Gache, Paul; Orléans, France, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Gadeyne, Roger; Liége, Belgique, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Gambau, Vincent; Paris, France, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Gargour, Edouard; Egypte, 1956-1958, 1960-1961, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Garneau, M. L’Abbé Jacques; Québec, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Gaston, Roger; Paris, France, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Germain, L’Abbé Victorin; Québec, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Gignac, Eugene; Québec, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Gillespie, W.E.; New Hampshire, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Giraud, J.; Lyon, France, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Giraud-Lindsay, Madame; California, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Giroux, Pierre Marcel; Paris, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Greenfield; Mrs. Henry; Houston, Texas, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Godeau, G.L.; France, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Godin, Frère C.-A.; Québec, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Goff, Mother Hildegard; Ursuline Academy; New York, 1941-1942, 1944, 1946, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Goldegar, Harry; New York, 1957-1958, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Goube, Pére Pierre; Alabama, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Goulet, Alexandre; Pennsylvania, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Grassin, Jean; Paris, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Greene, Mrs. Tatiana W.; New York, 1958-1963 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Gressier, André; Vieux-Condé, France, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Groholski, Mrs. Fred; Texas, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Grosperrin, Renée; Washington D. C., 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Guerena, Jacinto-Luis; Toulon, France, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Guerin, Georges; Bruxelles, Belgique, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Guide Franco-Américain; Rhode Island, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Guitelman, Helene; Brésil, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Guy, Malvina; Avignon, France, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Harris, P., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Harrod, Françoise; California, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Hauseux, Jacques; Bruxelles, Belgique, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Hédont, Marcel; Suisse, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Hédoul, Marcel F., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Hendrix, G.; Angleur, Belgique, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Hermelin, Henriette; New York, 1957-1963 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Hiller, C.F.; University of Houston, 1946, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Hodgins, Eric; New York, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Houston Chamber of Commerce, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Institut d’Études Occitanes; Toulouse, France, 1948, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Institut Français d’Athens; Grèce, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Institut International de Tours; Tours, France, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Ipoustguy, Jean; Choisy-le-Roi, France, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Jack, Alta; Texas, 1942, 1944, 1946-1947, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - De Jaire, Edmond, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Jeter, Mrs. J. E.; California, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Job, H. J.; Houston, 1946, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Johnson, Mrs. Cone H.; Texas, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Jullien, Alfred R.; Massachusetts, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Kanaraki, Marika; Istanbul, Türkriye, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Kelly, Geraldine; California, undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Kieffer, Joseph; Canada, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Knepper, Mrs. David W.; Texas, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Koomey, Winston; Texas, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Labaye, Gérard; Belgique, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Lacost Printing Company, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Lacourcière, Luc; Québec, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Laroque Tinker, Edward; New York, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Lavergne, Louis; Canada, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Lebàgue, Abbé Felicien; Montjavoult, France, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Le Breton, Eileen; London, 1960, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Le Cercle du Livre de France; New York, 1949-1951 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Leduc, Fernande; Montréal, Canada, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Legier, Andre; Bruxelles, Belgique, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Le Guen; Jean-Yves; Oram, Algérie, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Le Maitre, Henri; France, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Lenof, Felix; Houston, Texas, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - La Ligue Missionnaire des Étudiants; Montréal, Canada, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Lindblom, Ruey Joan; Wisconsin, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Loftus, Elizabeth Thérese; Massachusetts, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Loir, Raymond; Beyrouth, Liban, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Loisy, Jean; Paris, France, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Looten, Emmanuel; Paris, France, 1949, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Los Angeles Valley College Library; California, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Loward, Robert; Liége, Belgique, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Lowe, Elizabeth; Louisiana, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Lucas, Roger; Paris, France, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Lukei, Norman Oskar; Argentina, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Madore, Valens; Maine, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Magnien, Moise; Paris, France, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Mahe, Guy; St. Brieuc, France, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Maison Internationale de la Poésie; Belgique, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Malin, Jane W.; Paris, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Mandel, Salomé; Washington D.C., 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Mariat, Madeleine; Suisse, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Marietti, Angéle; Paris, France, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Marjan; France, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Masques: Revue Internationale Illustré d’Art Dramatique; Paris, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Massis, Armand; Bruxelles, Belgique, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Masotti, M.; Texas, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Maurice, Robert R.; St. Etienne, France, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Mantha, Hector; Texas, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Maquale, Mademoiselle; Pointe-a-Pitre, Guadeloupe, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Marc, Jean; Bruxelles, Belgique, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Marley, Anna; Philadelphia, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Martin, Juanita; Texas, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Marshall, Robert F.; Denton, Texas, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Marty, Gerard; Paris, France, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Matte, J. Adolphus; Montréal, Canada, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Mayer, Mrs. Ralph; Michigan, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Meraville, Marie-Aimée; France, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Meshaka, Madame; France, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Messis, Blanche; Nice, France, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Milet, A.; Paris, France, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Millérioux, M.; Nice, France, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Milligan, Vincent; New York, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Minarelli, Tiziano; Italie, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Miranda, Tauresde; Brésil, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1940, 1943, 1948, 1950-1954, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Mitchell, R.; London, England, 1961, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Moore, Russell F.; New York, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Moreel, Léon; Dunkerque, France, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Morot-Sir, Edouard; New York, French Embassy, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Morphos, Panos; New Orléans, Louisiana, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Morris, Lillian; Massachusetts, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Moulé, M.J.; Florida, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Moulé, M.J.; Florida, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Muldrow, Louise; Texas, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Mülhenheim, Frédéric E. Tennessee, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Muller, Frans; Belgique, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Murfey, Josephean; Florida, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Naniche, Georges; Netherlands, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Nelson, Paula; New York, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Newman, Alfred, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Newman, Edwin; Virginia, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Newman, Rigel; Virginia, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Nichols, Roma; London, England, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - De Niezabytowska, Solange; Italie, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Nixon, Jack Lowell; California, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Nogués, Germinal; Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Novembre, Jean; France, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - N. R.F.; France, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Nykl, A.R.; Wisconsin, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Oberty, Luce; France, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 157)